Bhavesh Mahendra Sanghvi

♦ +1 (509) 592-1343■ jainbhavesh.07@gmail.com

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/bhaveshsanghvi/

https://github.com/bhaveshSanghvi

SUMMARY

Software Engineer for 4 years, designed and developed enterprise applications using various technologies. **Oracle Certified Professional, in Java Programming (OCPJP)**. **Object Oriented Design** in **Java** and **Problem solving** are my strengths. Extensively used frontend technologies like **AngularJS** and **JavaScript**. I also have working knowledge of **Machine learning** and **Data science**. High motivation and curiosity drive me to ensure delivery of production grade solutions. Have been part of 3 enterprise applications which are currently in production.

EDUCATION

■ Master's in Computer Science, Washington State University, Pullman

Expected May 2019

Relevant Coursework: Advanced Algorithms, Bigdata, Computational Genomics, Machine Learning, Data Science.

■ Bachelor's in Computer Engineering, University of Mumbai

July 2015

Coursework: Java Programming, Data structures, Algorithms, Databases, Software Design and Architecture.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: **Java8**, Python, PHP, C++ (basics)
- Frameworks: **Kafka**, REST, **Spring**, Hibernate, JDBC, J2EE
- Web and Application servers: Apache Tomcat, Oracle WebLogic, IBM WebSphere.
- Database: Oracle database, IBM DB2, MySQL, PostgreSQL.
- Front-end technology: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, **ReactJS**, **AngularJS**.
- Tools: GIT, Maven, IDE's (IntelliJ, Eclipse), JIRA, Swagger, Junit (Mockito framework), SONAR, Jenkins

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer | ASM America Inc.

Jul 2019 - Current

- Automated the manual process of software tool configuration generation by creating python scripts.
- Created a web application to access and perform dynamic changes to tool configuration through web services.

Software Developer | Enterprise Systems, Pullman, WA.

Sep 2017 – May 2019

- Designed and Implemented Several flows for data manipulation from one format to another using Groovy, XSLT. This
 increased performance of the existing system by reducing human effort and making it very efficient for usage.
- Designed and Implemented "SUPERVISOR MANAGEMENT" application using technologies like Spring, Java, Data tables framework, JWT token management, Restful web services.
- Designed and Developed Static Mobile applications related to campus requirements using AEK, ReactJS.

Software Engineer | L&T Infotech, India

Jul 2015 – Aug 2017

- Worked as a **Full stack Software Engineer** for clientele **Nordea Life Assurance**. Extensively took part in gathering requirements to making them a reality with active involvement in all domains of developments from the beginning.
- Implemented complex requirements like Mobile Token Authentication, Feeding and Retrieving data from Tridion Content Management System, RESTful web services using Java and Jersey framework, front-end Integration of Web services using AngularJS and JavaScript. Handled every requirement that came my way and ensured successful delivery before time.
- My role was to handle development as well as the deployment of the product. Integrated GIT, Maven, and Jenkins as tools and maintained dev and test environments using Oracle WebLogic. Increased performance using SONAR, worked in an agile environment among a team of 10, and possess good knowledge of Scrum, Jira, and Confluence.

PROJECTS

- **Book Recommendation System**: Implemented a book recommendation system based on co-purchasing pattern analysis using associations obtained from FP growth algorithm. Used Python, Keras, **Springboot**.
- Credit Card Fraud Detection: (Python) Performed Data Exploration, Exploratory Data analysis, Data transformation, Data visualization, applied Machine learning and Deep learning algorithms to create models to detect fraud in credit card transactions.
- Online Banking Application: Analyzed banking use cases like Account Creation, Fund Transfer, Transaction Summary and Session Management. Created and implemented the use case in Java, JSP-Servlet, by making extensive use of Object-Oriented design patterns like Singleton pattern and DAO pattern